本:走吧,走吧,走吧.我们要迟到了.
Ben: Let's go, lets go, lets go. We are going to be late.
杰森:本,你不用叫.
Jason: Ben. You don't have to yell.
本:我肯定要叫,我激动.
Ben: Sure, I'm excited.
杰森:那你出去.
Jason: Then go outside.
本:到底怎么回事,这么长时间?我们得走了.
Ben: What the heck's taking so long? We got to move.
杰森:进去,本.
Jason: Inside Ben.
本:对不起,爸爸.我没能控制好我自己.
Ben: I'm sorry dad. I lost control.
杰森:这儿的人都知道.
Jason: Everyone on the block knows it.
本:我控制不住.有多少孩子在周五参加"考斯比节目"的现场录制呢?
Ben: I can't help it.
How many kids get to spend their Friday night at a live taping of The
Cosby Show?
杰森:我也很兴奋,本,但是你没有听到我叫吧.咱们走吧!
Jason: I'm excited too Ben, but you don't hear me yelling. Let's go!
本:妈妈和开萝尔怎么回事,拖这么久?
Ben: What's taking mum and Carol so darn long?
杰森:是这样的,本,我觉得你也长大了,应该了解这个了.
Jason: Well Ben, I guess you are finally old enough to hear this.
本:什么?
Ben: What?
杰森:女人总是迟到.
Jason: Women are always late.
本:为什么?
Ben: Why?
杰森:没人知道,本.以前是这样子,现在还是这样子.
Jason: No-one knows Ben. It's just the way it is and always has been.
本:我们可以不管她们.
Ben: We could leave without them.
杰森:你应该了解的另外一件事,也是关于女人的,就是你挖苦她们的时候,她们就恨你.
Jason: Well this is it. The next thing you have to learn about women Ben
is that they hate it when you ditch them
本:为什么她们总是迟到呢?
Ben: Why are they always late?
杰森:我没说女人是理性动物.
Jason: I didn't say that women made sense.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:我是说她们非常的理性.咱们还是面对现实吧,本,
Jason: I said they make tremendous sense.
她们是比我们强.哦,
Let's face it Ben, they are better than us. Oh you look great.
你看起来可真漂亮.你看,她是不是看起来……你看起来……我这就把车打着.
Well does she look...You look..I'm going to start the car.
本:我们是不是还得等开萝尔?
Ben: Do we have to wait for Carol too?
麦琪:她是你姐姐.
Maggie: She's your sister.
开萝尔:我看起来如何?
Carol: All set. How do I look?
麦琪:太棒了.迈克,我们走了.
Maggie: Great. Mike, we're leaving.
迈克:好的.好好玩啊.嗨,
Mike: Ok. You guys have fun. Hey Carol, come on.
开萝尔,得了吧,你还没有完事啊?
Aren't you going to go get ready?
开萝尔:祝愿你今晚的约会成为你整个一生中最羞辱的一幕.
Carol: May your date tonight turn out to be the most embarrassing event
of your entire life.
本:迈克,
Ben: Mike, I don't get it.
我不明白,你怎么会整天和那些不可理喻的女孩混在一起,
How could you go and mess around with some stupid girl,
你可以在电视上看到收视率最高的电视节目的啊.
when you could see the taping of the number one show on TV.
迈克:当青春期降临的时候,你就会明白了,本.
Mike: When puberty hits, you'll get it Ben.
本:爸爸已经跟我聊过女人了,我没什么感觉.
Ben: Dad already told me about girls. I'm not impressed.
杰森:这不是一个很好的结局么?
Jason: Well, wasn't that a great ending?
本:我错过了,难以置信,我居然错过了,哦,不!青春期!
Ben: I missed it. I can't believe I missed it. Oh no! Puberty!
迈克:好了.我搞定了.
Mike: Alright, I made it.
本:啊--!
Ben: Ahh!
迈克:本,你在做什么?
Mike: What the...Ben, what are you doing?
本:迈克,我得跟你谈一谈,我不想错过你.
Ben: Mike, I had to talk to you and I didn't want to miss you.
迈克:你差点弄死我.
Mike: You almost killed me.
本:迈克,今晚发生了件怪事.
Ben: Mike, something weird happened tonight.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
本:青春期.
Ben: Puberty.
迈克:哦,出去.
Mike: Oh get out of here.
本:我不开玩笑.我放声大笑,
Ben: I'm not kidding.
过得很愉快,不过,突然间,
I mean there I was laughing, having a great time,
这望过去看到有一位姑娘,她正在看着我,
and all of a sudden I look over and there's this girl and she's looking
于是乎她离开了(挥手),然后是"嘣"的一声.
at me real funny and she goes (waves), and bang.
我听到这种怪异的音乐,觉得所有的一切都琢磨不透,我紧张出汗.
I heard this weird kind of music and everything looked goofy and I was
我觉得,我的身体不舒服了.
sweating. I felt, I don't know, like my body didn't fit anymore.
迈克:那是青春期,一点儿没错.
Mike: Yep, that's puberty all right.
本:低俗.我怎么才能阻止青春期?
Ben: It was gross. How do I stop it?
迈克:你办不到的,本.没有人能阻止青春期.
Mike: You can't Ben. You see, nobody stops puberty.
本:那它会持续多久?
Ben: How long does it last?
迈克:谁也不知道,也许永远都不会停.比如,麦克*福克思.
Mike: Well, you never know. It could last forever. Look at Michael J Fox.
本:我不知道该如何是好.
Ben: I'm confused.
迈克:你才刚刚开始了解它,本.
Mike: Yeah, well, you just got to learn to live with it Ben.
本:好像你已经经历过了?
Ben: Like you have?
迈克:对.
Mike: Right.
本:不过,
Ben: But I don't want to make a total jerk out of myself every time a
我不想每次有女孩走进来的时候都紧张难受.
girl walks into the room.
迈克:谁告诉你我那样了?
Mike: Who says I do that?
本:妈妈.
Ben: Mum.
迈克:得了,听好了,
Mike: Alright, well look.
这一回你得相信我说的话,本.
You're just going to have to take my word on this one Ben.
事实上,青春期太美妙了,
Now puberty is fantastic.
就像是在娱乐园里,到处都是女孩.
I mean, it's like an amusement park filled with girls.
本:我不喜欢女孩.
Ben: I hate girls.
迈克:哦,好了,本.想一想,你真的不喜欢女孩么?
Mike: Oh come on Ben. Think about that. Do you really hate girls?
本:不喜欢.不不,喜欢.
Ben: Yes. No. No I don't hate girls.
迈克:太棒了,太棒了.
Mike: Crazy, crazy.
本:对于女孩我一无所知,我对她们该说些什么?
Ben: I don't know anything about girls. What do I say to them?
迈克:本,听着……
Mike: Ben, listen...
本:讲讲女孩,迈克.求你了,求求你了.
Ben: Explain girls Mike. Please please please.
迈克:本,你应该跟爸爸谈.
Mike: Ben, you are going to have to talk to dad. Ok.
本:我办不到,这话题太私密了,帮帮我!
Ben: I can't do that. This is private. Help me!
迈克:听着,本.
Mike: Listen Ben. I'll be straight with you.
我会对你推心置腹的.
Dad made me promise that if you ever came to me with any questions on sex...
爸爸曾让我保证过,如果你问我任何问题只要是关于性方面的……我必须滴水不漏.
I wouldn't say a word.
本:谁在跟你谈性了?我只是想谈女孩.
Ben: Who's talking about sex? I want to know about girls.
本:嗨.
Ben: Hi.
麦琪:早上好,本.
Maggie: Morning Bennie.
杰森:你刮完之后才穿么?
Jason: Are you wearing after shave?
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
杰森:为什么?
Jason: Why?
本:我也不知道.如果我不说话,
Ben: I don't know. Would you guys mind if I didn't talk.
你们会介意么,我有事想思考一下.
I've got stuff to think about.
杰森:好好想吧.
Jason: Think away.
麦琪:杰森,你还知道什么是乐趣么?
Maggie: Jason, do you know what would be fun?
今晚你我二人出去约会去.
Tonight you and I go out on a date.
杰森:约会.
Jason: Date.
麦琪:看来你没忘.我们十来岁的时候,我们常去约会.
Maggie: You remember those. We used to have them when we were teenagers.
杰森:以前那些约会.
Jason: Those.
麦琪:我们穿戴整齐,出去吃晚餐,
Maggie: We could get all dressed up, go out for a nice dinner,
跳支舞.自从上次之后,我们有多久没那么做了?
a little dancing. I mean how long has it been since we've done that?
杰森`:迈克多大?
Jason: How old is Mike?
麦琪:那跟这有什么关系?
Maggie: How about it sailor?
杰森:(支吾)
Jason: Well, I oo, aaa, eee
杰森:好了,本,你怎么想的?得到了什么建议了么?
Jason: Come on Ben, what do you think? You got any advice?
本:我连你约会的时候会怎么做都不知道.
Ben: I don't even know what you are supposed to do on a date.
杰森:你出去.祝你玩得开心.
Jason: Well you go out. Have a good time.
本:干什么呢?
Ben: Doing what?
杰森:这样的,
Jason: Well it doesn't matter exactly what you're doing Ben.
你具体干什么并不重要,本.
What matters is that you are spending time with the one who captured your
重要的是你和自己心仪的人共同相处.
heart.
本:你怎么知道她是不是让你心仪呢?
Ben: How do you know if she captured your heart?
杰森:她掏腰包.
Jason: She pays.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:开个玩笑.你知道我是在开玩笑吧,本?
Jason: Just kidding. You know I'm kidding, don't you Ben?
本:哦,知道.
Ben: Oh yeah.
杰森:有人请你约会了,亲爱的?
Jason: Well then you got a date honey.
麦琪:哦,太棒了,我要去叫一个保姆.
Maggie: Oh great. I'll go call a sitter.
本:我不要保姆.
Ben: I don't need a baby sitter.
麦琪:不,你需要,本.
Maggie: Yes you do Ben.
本:爸爸!
Ben: Dad!
杰森:以前咱们都熬过来了,本.
Jason: We've been through this before Ben.
本:哦,太好了.一整晚,无聊透顶,要和一个12岁的女孩呆在一起.
Ben: Oh great. A whole stupid boring night with a twelve year old girl. Hmmm...
迈克:嗨,宝贝.发生了什么事?
Mike: Hey babe. What's happening?
本:你怎么跟你自个儿在说话呢?
Ben: How come you are talking to yourself?
迈克:不是在跟我自个说话,我是在排练举措呢.
Mike: I'm not talking to myself. I'm just rehearsing my moves.
本:什么是举措?
Ben: What are moves?
迈克:你在女孩身上施展的东西.
Mike: They're what you put on girls.
本:哦,耶!你为什么要这么做?
Ben: Oh yeah! How come you do that?
迈克:让自己看起来更酷,本.
Mike: In order to look cool Ben.
把自己扮得很酷跟自己真的很酷一样重要.
You see it's just as important t to look cool as it is to be cool.
本:但是,你穿的裤子是旧的.
Ben: But you are wearing your old pants.
迈克:对,
Mike: Well yeah. I mean although it is important to look cool,
我的意思是说,虽然把自己扮得很酷很重要,
the worst thing I could do is make it look like I went out of my
但是为此改变自己则很糟糕.
way for this fox.
本:为什么?
Ben: Why?
迈克:为什么!本,
Mike: Why! Ben look, girls don't like guys who are wimps.
听好了,女孩不喜欢循规蹈矩的男孩,
They like guys who are a little bit unpredictable.
她们喜欢有点让人意外的男生,
Kind of guy who's a little bit dangerous.
甚至还有点危险的那种男生,什么时候都能惹出点乱子的男生.
The kind of guy who can get into trouble at any moment.
本:那,赫曼的约会可能多得自己都忙不过来.
Ben: So Pee Wee Herman probable has more dates than he can handle.
迈克:出去,出去,本.
Mike: Get out. Get out Ben.
杰森:咱们走吧,走吧,走吧!
Jason: Let's go, lets go, lets go!
迈克:爸爸,我想告诉你一点小小的秘密,
Mike: Dad, I'm going to let you in on a little secret ok.
女人总是迟到.
Girls are always late.
杰森:真的么?
Jason: Really?
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:那,今晚的幸运女孩会是谁呢?
Jason: So who's the lucky girl tonight?
迈克:我今晚和希娜*布鲁克维茨出去,待会儿见,爸爸.
Mike: Well, I'm going out with Sheena (woo woo) Burkavitz. See you later dad.
杰森:来啊,麦琪.预订保留到7:30.
Jason: Woo woo! Come one Maggie. The reservations for seven thirty.
开萝尔:你们要迟到了,再见.
Carol: Well, you're going to be late. See you.
杰森:等等,让我把这解释明白,你去哪儿?
Jason: Wait wait, let me get this straight. You are going where?
开萝尔:博比要带我去看电影,我在前廊上等他,
Carol: Bobby's taking me to a movie and I'm waiting for him on the front
因为来这儿的话他得跟你说话,
porch because when he comes here he has to talk to you,
那样他会紧张的,
and that makes him nervous,
所以我决定在外面等他,免得他受此折磨.
so I figured I'd wait for him outside and spare him the pain.
杰森:呵,想得多周全.
Jason: Well, how thoughtful.
特鲁迪:哇,我还没按门铃呢.
Trudy: Wow. Like, I didn't even ring yet.
开萝尔:再见,特鲁迪.
Carol: Bye Trudy.
特鲁迪:再见.嗨,希佛大夫,对不起,我迟到了.
Trudy: Bye. Hi Doctor Seaver. Sorry I'm late.
杰森:哦,没关系的,特鲁迪,没有女人不迟到.
Jason: Oh that's ok Trudy. Al women are.
麦琪:所有女人都什么?
Maggie: All women are what?
杰森:嗨,我是杰森*希佛,我是您今晚的护花使者,请问您是?
Jason: Well hi. I'm Jason Seaver. I'm your date this evening. And you are?
麦琪:着急人,哦,
Maggie: Anxious. Oh Trudy,
特鲁迪,餐厅的电话号码放在电话机旁了.冰箱里有东西,
the phone number for the restaurant is by the phone,
自己随意.大概十一点钟我们就会回来.
help yourself to anything in the refrigerator, we'll be back around eleven.
特鲁迪:好的.
Trudy: Right.
杰森:本!
Jason: Ben!
本:我还在洗澡桶里呢.
Ben: I'm still in the stupid bath tub.
麦琪:他在冲淋浴.
Maggie: He's taking a shower.
杰森:今天是他第三次.
Jason: That's his third one today.
麦琪:也许他会为去年补偿的,我们走了,本.
Maggie: Maybe he can make up for last year. We're leaving Ben.
本:好的.
Ben: Ok.
麦琪:晚安,特鲁迪.
Maggie: Night Trudy.
杰森:再见,特鲁迪.
Jason: See you Trudy.
特鲁迪:晚安.
Trudy: Night.
本:嗨,宝贝,发生了什么事?
Ben: Hey babe. What's happening?
本脑海中的声音:到底这儿是怎么回事?我用尽了我的招儿数,她看起来像是无动于衷.
Voice in Bens head: What the heck's going on here?
等一等.她刚才说的是什么?女人是非理性的.
I'm using all my moves and she acts like she doesn't care. Wait a minute.
哇,我觉得,
What did dad say? Women don't make sense.
事情正朝着应该的发向发展.目前为止,一切正常.
Wow, so I guess it's going the way it's supposed to. So far, so good.
特鲁迪:本,别再出丑了.呃!
Trudy: Ben, stop clowning around. Hu!
本:什么?
Ben: What?
特鲁迪:走开,你在干什么?
Trudy: Get away from me. What are you doing?
本:这些垃圾我有的是,
Ben: I've had enough of this junk.
我有心情做些出人意料的事情,有些危险的事情.
I'm in the mood to do something unpredictable. Something dangerous.
我就是喜欢惹麻烦的那种男生.
I don't know. I'm just the kind of kid who likes to get in trouble.
特鲁迪:你可最好别,小子.这是我得到的最好的保姆工作,
Trudy: You'd better not young man.
我可不想丢了它.现在,
This is the best babysitting job I've got, and I'm not about to loose it.
坐下,安静,否则我送你上床睡觉.
Now sit still and be quiet or I'll send you to bed.
本脑海里的声音:这是我一生中最差的一夜.
Voice in Bens head: This is the worst night of my life.
迈克:这是我一生中最差的一夜,真让我难以置信.我站起来了,我,
Mike: This is the worst night of my life. I can't believe this.
迈克*希佛,站起来了.你会相信么?
I was stood up. Me, Mike Seaver, stood up. Can you believe that?
本:我肯定会.
Ben: I sure can.
迈克:就是这样了.我和女人有过了.
Mike: That's it. I have had it with women.
特鲁迪:我是不是应该打电话叫我家人过来把我接走.
Trudy: Should I call my folks to come get me.
迈克:对极了,继续,
Mike: Yeah sure, go ahead. Just going to hang out here with Ben.
本,为什么穿成那个样子?本.
Ben, why are you dressed like that? Bennie.
本:迈克,请不要那样,迈克,请不要那样.
Ben: Mike. Please don't Mike. Please don't.
迈克:本,你把招儿用到你的保姆身上了么?
Mike: Bennie are you putting the moves on your baby sitter?
本:啊----!
Ben: Ahhhh!
迈克:对,鲍纳.
Mike: Yeah Boner. I got some news about my date. With woo woo Burkavitz.
我得到一些关于我约会的消息.和布鲁克维茨.
Yeah. You're not going to believe this, but I got stood up.
你不会相信的,但是我起来了.
Oh, why is that so easy for you to believe? Yeah, well anyway.
哦,为什么你会轻信那个?
I just wanted you to know that as of tonight I am taking a break from
好了,我只是想让你知道今晚我在女人这有了历史性的进展.
women.
(打开门)
(Opens door)
女孩:嗨.
Girl: Well hi.
迈克:嗨,宝贝,发生了什么事?
Mike: Breaks over. Hey babe. What's happening?
女孩:没什么,我是特鲁迪的姐姐,
Girl: Well not much. I'm Trudy's sister.
我开车来接她回去.
I had to drive all the way over here to pick her up.
迈克:你开车?那你有16了?
Mike: You drive? So you are sixteen?
女孩:18.
Girl: Eighteen.
迈克:18.18岁太好了.嗨,真太巧了.
Mike: Eighteen. Eighteen's good. Hey, what a coincidence.
女孩:马路上的那个是你的车么?
Girl: Is that your convertible in the driveway?
迈克:对,你想要么?
Mike: Yeah. It sure is. Do you want it?
女孩:我叫斯泰茜.
Girl: I'm Stacey.
迈克:我叫迈克.
Mike: Mike.
特鲁迪:我烦了.
Trudy: I'm bored.
斯泰茜:哦,耶,得走了,非常高兴见到你.
Stacey: Oh yeah. Well, um, it was nice meeting you.
迈克:我也一样.喂,有时间你喜不喜欢出去蹓达蹓达?
Mike: Same here. Say, um, would you like to go out sometime?
斯泰茜:哦,我很喜欢,不过,
Stacey: Oh I'd love to. But I'm only in town for the weekend.
我只有这周末在城里.我得回乔治城.我在那上大学.
I have to go back to George Town. University.
迈克:你上大学了?
Mike: You go to college?
斯泰茜:对,你呢?
Stacey: Yeah. You?
迈克:呣,又是一个巧合.那,今晚怎么样?
Mike: Uh, another coincidence. Well, what about tonight?
斯泰茜:哦,不过,约会是不是有点太晚了.
Stacey: Oh well, it's a little late for a date.
特鲁迪:如果你现在出去,爸爸会气疯的.
Trudy: If you went out now, dad would have a cow.
斯泰茜:你怎么知道的,特鲁迪?迈克,事实上,我有点累了.
Stacey: What do you know Trudy? Mike, well, the truth is, I'm a bit tired.
特鲁迪:对.咱们能走了么?
Trudy: Yeah right. Can we go?
斯泰茜:在车里等.小孩儿!
Stacey: Wait in the car. Kids!
迈克:如此年幼,如此急躁.
Mike: So young, so impatient.
斯泰茜:这样的,我三周后回来.
Stacey: Well, I'm coming back in three weeks.
迈克:三周.我的意思是说,我们可以想些变通的办法.
Mike: Three weeks. I mean, yeah, we could work something out.
斯泰茜:对,你可以到华盛顿特区来.
Stacey: Yeah, you could come down to DC.
迈克:华盛顿特区!不,
Mike: DC! No I don't think my folks,
我们家人,我是说我的那辆大众车可能不行的.
I mean my voltswagen is going to make it.
这样的,我也只是周末才回家.
See um, I'm just visiting home for the weekend too.
斯泰茜:哦,那你在哪儿上学?
Stacey: Oh, where do you go to school?
迈克:耶鲁.
Mike: Yale.
斯泰茜:哇!
Stacey: Wow!
迈克:是啊,从特区到波士顿,真的是要开上很长时间.
Mike: Yeah, you see it would be a real long drive from DC to Boston.
斯泰茜:波士顿!耶鲁在新罕默什尔,在波士顿的是哈佛.
Stacey: Boston! Yale's in New Haven. Harvard's in Boston.
迈克:哦,对,看我,
Mike: Oh um, right, See I make that mistake all the time.
无时无刻不在犯错误.耶鲁的奖学金让我给拒绝了,我接受的是哈佛的奖学金.
See I turned down the Yale scholarship and took the one from Harvard instead.
斯泰茜:哦,我的小妹妹等不及了.
Stacey: Oh, my little sister is freaking out.
迈克:对,知道么,
Mike: Yeah, you know. My little brother probably drove her to it.
可能是我弟弟害的.他最近才对女孩有感觉,
See he only recently discovered girls and uh,
呣,特鲁迪可能会有意外的收获.
maybe Trudy got a little more than she bargained for.
斯泰茜:啊,那很甜蜜.不过……
Stacey: Ah, that's sweet. Well..
迈克:你知道这很甜蜜,
Mike: Uh, you know it's very sweet and you know what really gets me is
而且你还知道我心里的感受;我此时的感受,就如同我弟弟对自己来电的女孩一样的难以割舍,
that the first crush my little brother has on a girl she has to go home
而这个女孩却要早早回家.
early.
斯泰茜:哦,真让人害臊.
Stacey: Oh that's a shame.
迈克:害臊,它还要害命.
Mike: A shame. It's a crime.
斯泰茜:好了,
Stacey: Well, I think it's just as wrong that my little sister is denied
我个人觉得妹妹拒绝某些善意的挑逗不是太好.
the experience of some innocent flirting.
迈克:我完全赞同你的看法.同时,
Mike: Um, you know couldn't agree more and with the way the world going
按照今天世界的发展趋势来看,我认为,这俩个小孩子很可能自己跌跌撞撞步入青春期,
today, I think that these two kids might stumble into puberty without
即使他们周围没人成年人----比方说你,还有我.
adults like you and me around.
斯泰茜:哦,那岂不是有些骇人.
Stacey: Oh, that's frightening.
迈克:这只是个设想.
Mike: That's the idea.
斯泰茜:我要找我妹妹去了.
Stacey: I'll get my sister.
迈克:好吧.
Mike: Ok.
本:得了!白折腾,都是为他人做嫁衣裳.
Ben: Alright! Mr. and Mrs. Jones. Here is your train.
迈克:本,我的好兄弟,你怎么这样.
Mike: Bennie, my man. There you are.
本:让我清静会儿,迈克.
Ben: Leave me alone Mike.
迈克:听着,本,我要你上楼去,特鲁迪在楼上.
Mike: Look Ben, I need you upstairs. Trudy's up there.
本:迈克,我已经把女孩看透了.
Ben: Mike, I'm through with girls.
迈克:你怎么会,本.你才刚刚开始.
Mike: You can't be Ben. You haven't even started yet.
本:我在想出家人的生活.
Ben: I'm thinking about the priesthood.
迈克:好吧,好吧.也许今天你确实诸事不利.
Mike: Alright, alright. So maybe things haven't gone so well for you today.
本:迈克,她嘲笑我.
Ben: Mike, she laughed at me.
迈克:本,女人没有不嘲笑男人的,
Mike: So. Ben, all women laugh at guys. You just gotta get used to it.
你得适应.你可不能放弃.
This is no time to give up.
本:哦,没问题,迈克.
Ben: Oh good Mike. You just squished Mr. and Mrs. Jones.
迈克:听着,本.我会把我要做的告诉你,
Mike: Look Ben. I'm going to tell you what I'm going o do.
我会把应该让你知道的关于女人的知识告诉你,这样,
I'm going to tell you all you need to know about women,
你就可以地回到楼上,转败为胜,征服特鲁迪.
so you can go right back up there and have the last laugh on Trudy. Ok?
本:她无动于衷.
Ben: She doesn't care.
迈克:无动于衷!好了,本.
Mike: Doesn't care! Come on Ben. Don't fall for her little act.
她的小把戏,你可不要上当.听我的,
Now listen to me, all girls do and say the opposite of what they mean.
所有的女孩的言,行都与她的真实想法刚好相反.不要告诉我你连这个都不知道.
And don't tell me you didn't know that.
本:我当然知道,只是有时候想不起来了.
Ben: Course I did, I just forgot for a minute.
迈克:好了,现在你上楼去么,还是打算呆在楼下,胆怯,放弃?
Mike: Alright, now are you going to go back up there or are you going
to stay down here and wimp out
本:可是我不知道该对她说些什么,
Ben: But I don't know what to say to her.
我不知道该怎么待她.
I don't know how to act with her.
迈克:好了,好了.目前,唯一的最重要的就是作贱自己.
Mike: Ok, ok. Now the single most important thing is not to embarrass yourself.
本:好.
Ben: Ok.
迈克:好,那就是说,不要生气.
Mike: Ok. That means no belching.
本:从不?
Ben: Ever?
迈克:从不,至少在她和你一起的时候不要生气.
Mike: Well, at least not when you're with her.
本:明白了.
Ben: Gotcha.
迈克:好了,不许得意忘形.
Mike: Ok, no screaming.
本:当然不会.
Ben: Of course not.
迈克:好.最重要的事情是,
Mike: Ok and the most important thing Ben,
本,沉得住气不要喜形于色.
don't have anything with you that's alive.
本:哦.
Ben: Oh.
特鲁迪:让我走,让我走!
Trudy: Let me go, let me go!
他不就是个傻乎乎的小孩儿么,我才不在乎他呢.
He's just a stupid little kid and I don't care about him.
斯泰茜:闭上你的嘴,装着喜欢他的样子.
Stacey: You keep your mouth shut and you pretend to like him.
照我说的去做,为了我.
And you do it for me.
本:嗨.
Ben: Hi.
特鲁迪:嗯.
Trudy: Sure.
迈克:呣,看,
Mike: Um, look, why don't you two finish watching a movie and I'll show
你们俩为什么不把电影一块儿看完呢?我带斯泰茜看看厨房.
Stacey the kitchen.
斯泰茜:能看看你们家的厨房,我很高兴
Stacey: I would love to see the kitchen.
本:我知道你爱的.
Ben: I understand you love me.
特鲁迪:不,一点儿都不.
Trudy: Not at all.
本:好,非常好.我也不喜欢你.
Ben: Good, very good. I don't like you either.
迈克:至于这个玩意儿就是我们称作电冰箱的东东.
Mike: And this is what I like to call the refrigerator.
斯泰茜:哇!
Stacey: Uh hu!
迈克:想摸一摸么?那,其它还有什么我可以展示给你呢?
Mike: Want to touch it? So what else can I show you?
特鲁迪:本,不要.
Trudy: Ben stop that.
本:不.
Ben: Yeah right.
迈克:根据我耶鲁大学,啊,
Mike: So you see, according to my sociology professor at Hale, uh Yarvard,
哈佛大学的社会学教授所讲,
at college, um, the single greatest barrier between male female relations,
男女两性间唯一的最大的障碍就是初吻的紧张不安.
is tension about the first kiss.
现在,我们就做这件事情并且以此克服这种紧张不安.
Now, we could just do that right now and get it over with.
斯泰茜:不过,你知道,我不……
Stacey: Well, you know, I just don't...
迈克:不,你明白的,
Mike: yeah, you see. I feel so much better.
我感觉好多了,我感觉又像是个高中生了.
I feel like a high school boy again.
斯泰茜:你以前是从哪里高中毕业的?
Stacey: Where did you graduate from?
迈克:杜威高中.
Mike: Dewey High.
斯泰茜:你是杜威高中的!我也是!86班的.
Stacey: You're a hooter! I'm a Hooter! Class of eighty six.
迈克:对,太巧了.
Mike: Yeah, what a coincidence.
斯泰茜:你肯定没来过我们班,否则我会记得你的.
Stacey: You couldn't have been in my class. I'd have remembered you.
迈克:呣,当时我比现在可矮多了,
Mike: Um, well, I was much shorter then. You should have looked down.
你会看不上我的.那就是当时的我.
There I was.
特鲁迪:你的手直出汗,我的背上流的到处都是.
Trudy: Your hand is sweating all over my back.
(他亲吻她)
(He kisses her)
特鲁迪:(大笑)
Trudy: Yuk!
本:欢迎你.
Ben: You're welcome.
特鲁迪:再试一次,我就杀了你.
Trudy: Try it again and I'll slug you.
本:等会儿,你真的是说你真的不喜欢我么?
Ben: Wait a minute; are you really saying you really don't like me?
特鲁迪:本,你就是一个傻乎乎的笨小孩儿,长了双汗手.
Trudy: Ben, you are just a stupid little kid with sweaty hands.
本:就是这样,我和女孩已经有过了.
Ben: That's it. I've had it with girls.
我为你打扮的整整齐齐,可是我又不能这样告诉你;你说的话总是和你的真实意图相反,
I got all dressed up for you and I wasn't supposed to tell you that.
可是你对自己说的话真的很认真.这实在太难了.
You say the opposite of what you mean, but you really mean it.
在我去看"考斯比秀"之前,一切曾是如此的简单明了.
This is too hard. Everything was so simple before I went to the Cosby Show.
特鲁迪:你去过"考斯比秀"的现场录制?亲自?
Trudy: You've been to a taping of the Cosby Show? In person.
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
特鲁迪:真的么?
Trudy: Really?
本:那样的事我们常做.
Ben: We do stuff like that all the time.
特鲁迪:哇!
Trudy: Wow!
斯泰茜:来,特鲁迪,我们不玩了.
Stacey: Come on Trudy, we're getting out of this play pen.
迈克:听着,我以前没有说我上大学啊,我只是说这是个巧合.
Mike: Look, I didn't say I went to college. I just said it was a coincidence.
斯泰茜:哦,那这巧合是什么?
Stacey: Oh, and what was the coincidence?
迈克:就是你去上大学了而我曾经……听说你上大学了.
Mike: Well, that you're going to college and I've...heard of it.
斯泰茜:就不能长大点!你为什么还坐在那儿?我说过了,回家.
Stacey: Grow up! Why are you still sitting there? I said let's go.
特鲁迪:我必须得走么?我和本正聊的开心.
Trudy: Do I have to? Ben and I are having a very interesting conversation.
斯泰茜:我们要走了.
Stacey: We're leaving.
特鲁迪:我很难过,本,我得走了.
Trudy: I'm sorry Ben, I have to go.
本:你真的很难过么?
Ben: You're really sorry?
特鲁迪:你在开玩笑?
Trudy: Are you kidding?
迈克:等会儿,我觉得你讨厌他.
Mike: Wait a minute, I thought you hated him.
特鲁迪:是的,但那是在我了解他之前.什么时候我们还能在聚一起,聊天?
Trudy: That's before I got to know him. When can we get together and talk.
本:我不知道,我会给你打电话的.
Ben: Um, gee, I don't know. I guess I'll call you.
特鲁迪:不不.我给你打,本杰明,再见.哇,"科斯比秀".
Trudy: No no. I'll call you. Benjamin, bye. Wow, the Cosby Show.
本:我还去过出卖费上万美元的迪克*克拉科的节目!
Ben: I've also been to the ten thousand dollar pyramid staring Mr. Dick Clark!
迈克:好了,好了,交易是什么?
Mike: Alright, alright, what's the deal?
本:什么交易?
Ben: What deal?
迈克:我想知道你对特鲁迪都说了些什么.
Mike: I want to know what you said to Trudy.
本:就你告诉我的那些.
Ben: Just what you told me to.
迈克:还有呢?
Mike: And what else?
本:就那些.
Ben: That's it.
迈克:得了,本.你还都说了些什么?告诉我.
Mike: Come on Ben. What else did you say? I need to know.
本:迈克,你是在向我征询关于女人的建议么?
Ben: Mike, are you asking my advice about women?
迈克:什么!得了,本,你都说了些什么?
Mike: What! Come on Ben, that's stupid. So, like, what did you say?
本:我还以为女人的事你无所不知呢.
Ben: I thought you knew everything about girls.
迈克:当然无所不知了.好了,也不见得所有都知道.但是,
Mike: Well of course I do. Ok, alright, maybe not everything.
很多都知道.好了,什么都不知道,零,零蛋.
But a lot, I know a whole lot. Ok nothing, zero, zip.
本:不过,我一直以为……
Ben: But I always thought...
迈克:你当然是了,本.我是说,你曾是一个眼睛像星星一样明亮的小孩儿.
Mike: Of course you did Ben. I mean, you were just a starry eyed little kid.
不过,现在是你了解真相的时候了,因为你长大了.
But I guess it's time you learned the truth, now that you are a guy.
本:我真的是大人了么?
Ben: I'm an actual guy?
迈克:对,小大人,不过,是大人.
Mike: Yeah, a small one, but yes.
本:我是大人,关于女孩我知道的和你一样多.
Ben: Gee, I'm a guy and I know as much about girls as you do.
迈克:你什么也不知道.
Mike: You know nothing.
本:呃!
Ben: Uh hu!
杰森:嗨,孩子们.
Jason: Hi guys
迈克和本:嗨.
Mike and Ben: Hi.
麦琪:你们起晚了.
Maggie: You're up late.
本:
Ben: We're having a night cap.
杰森:哦,自从你问过那些之后,我们有了一个很不错的姑娘.
Jason: Oh and since you asked, we had a great date.
麦琪:一点儿没错.好了,晚安.
Maggie: We sure did. Well goodnight.
杰森:什么,傍晚已经过去?
Jason: What, the evening's over?
麦琪:晚安,孩子们.
Maggie: Night boys.
本和迈克:晚安,妈妈.
Ben and Mike: Night mum.
杰森:明天早上再见.
Jason: See you in the morning.
迈克:爸爸,爸爸,您有时间么?
Mike: Dad, dad. You got a second?
杰森:事实上,我我……
Jason: Actually I, I...
迈克:事情很重要.
Mike: It's important.
杰森:什么事情?
Jason: What is it?
迈克:是这样的,本和我正在讨论女人,
Mike: Well um, see, me and Ben were discussing women and,
我们想了解一些你的想法.
we kind of wanted to know your thoughts.
杰森:你们两个刚才在讨论女人?
Jason: You two were discussing women?
本:对,我现在是大人了.好了,你是怎么想的?
Ben: Yeah, I'm a guy now. So what do you think?
迈克:我们需要知道的是,比如,
Mike: See what we got to know is,
在什么年龄段你们才最终了解女人?
like at what age did you finally understand women?
杰森:哈哈哈哈.
Jason: Ha ha ha ha.
本:有什么如此好笑?
Ben: What's so funny?
杰森:没事,
Jason: Well nothing. It seems like only yesterday I was asking my dad
看起来像是就在昨天我在问我爸爸完全一样的问题.
that exact question.
迈克:那是什么时候的事?
Mike: When was that?
杰森:昨天.
Jason: It was yesterday.
开萝尔:嗨,妈妈.
Carol: Hi mum.
麦琪:开萝尔,你吓了我一跳.你为什么坐在这儿,黑咕咙咚的?
Maggie: Carol, you startled me. Why are you sitting here in the dark?
开萝尔:啊,博比和我吵架了.
Carol: Ah Bobby and I are fighting.
麦琪:真替你难过,为什么呢?
Maggie: I'm sorry. Why?
开萝尔:他说如果我懂得一些道理的话我应该给他打电话.
Carol: He says I should call him if I ever decide to make sense.
麦琪:他真是太粗鲁了.
Maggie: Well that's pretty rude.
开萝尔:对,我也是这么想的.
Carol: Yeah, I thought so too.
麦琪:那,吃点蛋糕,你会感觉好受点儿?
Maggie: So you are having some cake so you feel better?
开萝尔:不,我不饿.你想吃蛋糕?
Carol: No. I'm not hungry. You want some cake?
麦琪:不,我从不这么晚吃蛋糕.
Maggie: No, I never eat cake this late.
开萝尔:妈妈,你了解男人么?
Carol: Mum, do you understand men?
麦琪:不了解,不过没关系,他们也不了解我们.
Maggie: No. But that's ok. They don't understand us either.
开萝尔:无法了解的是什么?
麦琪:你搞定我.
00:23:17,300
Carol: What's not to understand? Maggie: You got me.